# Kenan Bölükbaşı

Керан Андреев Давидов | Keran Andreev Davidov

# Game Developer & Designer, CG Generalist, Architect

### SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS

Theoretical and applied knowledge in programming, design and media. Broad experience in project management. Experience in 3D (mesh, solid & CAD), 2D (raster, vector), and parametric graphics as well as asset pipelines and tools development. Blender 3D specialist (Blender Foundation Certified Trainer).

#### PERSONAL DETAILS

CITIZENSHIP Turkish, Bulgarian

DRIVER'S LICENCE B Class

DATE & PLACE OF BIRTH 28th January 1987, Bulgaria

#### **EDUCATION**

2005 – 2017 Architecture (B.Arch.)

Istanbul Technical University, ITU School of Architecture, İstanbul

2001 – 2005 High School (Science and Math)

Nilüfer Milli Piyango Anatolian High School,

Bursa

## CONFERENCES & WORKSHOPS

#### TALKS GIVEN

Toxicity in Gaming: Negative Effects of Prioritizing Player Motivation in World Design
 ITU School of Architecture, Taşkışla, İstanbul
 Prototyping & Optimizing Game Asset Workflow
 Blender Conference, Amsterdam
 Automated Sprite Rendering System in Blender

Libre Graphics Meeting, Leipzig

2014 Blender Python Programming Workshop BlendFX Studios, Leipzig

2011 **AudioSpaces LiveCoding Workshop**ITU School of Architecture, Taşkışla, İstanbul

#### PARTICIPATION

2015 Game Developers Conference EU 2015 (Cologne)

UBM Tech

2014 Blender Conference (Amsterdam)
Blender Foundation

2014 Libre Graphics Meeting (Leipzig)
LGM Crew

2014 Blender Python Workshop (Leipzig) Kenan Bölükbaşı

2011 **IAF Compositing Workshop (İstanbul)** Özgür Gülbir

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

#### 6x13 Games, İstanbul

JAN 2015 - [ CONT'D ]

## Founder, Project Leader & Developer

Project leader. Game design and development. Graphic design and game asset creation. Prototyping, pipeline optimization.

- Design, development and artwork of WRECKJUMPER[WIP], forced-perspective sci-fi TBS with dynamic puzzle elements.
- Game design, development, project management, graphics and user interface design of TWINIWT, the globally featured free to play symmetrical movement puzzle.
- Project management & development of 1FPS GAME SERIES.
   4 free to play handheld console games. The titles are:

- 1FPS: INVADERS - 1FPS: VACUUM

- 1FPS: VACUUM - 1FPS: FASTFOOD

- 1FPS: GRAFFITI[WIP]
- Cocos2d-x based in-house cross-platform game framework.
- Data structure design and development of the visualization module for an architectural research project, FAÇADE, at ITU. It generates facades using evolutionary algorithms.
- Development of Fossicker, open source asset prospector.
- Invited industry participant at some Architectural Design Computing Master's Program classes at ITU.

# EKSERIYA STUDIOS, İSTANBUL AUG 2013 – JAN 2015

Graphics Department Lead & TD

Decision making on graphics technology and workflow. Workflow optimization software development. Game asset creation, shading and lighting. Pipeline integration and prototyping.

- Asset pipeline automation system (import, lighting, rendering, compositing & atlas) for mobile RTS, SILICON WARS.
- Environment art and map editor for RIOT DEFENSE game.
- Pseudo 3D graphics R&D for FOOTBALL WIZARD game assets.

#### FREELANCE, İSTANBUL

Jun 2011 - Feb 2014

# Visualization Artist

Archviz for various firms. Modeling & rendering of office furniture catalog of Bürosit as well as indoor visualizations.

# EFOR EVENTS & SIMMETRICO, BAKU AUG 2011 – SEP 2011 Assistant Site Manager

Construction site management of a large steel structure for the wedding event of Azerbaijani President İlham Aliyev's daughter, in a multinational (Italian, Turkish & Azerbaijani) environment.

# SosyalMedya.CO, İstanbul

FEB 2011 - MAR 2012

#### **Author**

Tech industry reports. Column in monthly e-journal. Interview with former Turkey & MEA Marketing Manager of Google.

#### EFOR EVENTS, İSTANBUL

JUL 2010 - APR 2013

#### **Event Supervisor**

Workflow & stage manager. Major events: Windows 8 Turkey Launch, Kenan Doğulu concert, VIP trip to Czech Republic. Clients: Microsoft, TeliaSonera, Huawei, Volvo, Doğuş, Soyak.

#### Aşçıoğlu İnşaat, İstanbul

SEP 2009 - Nov 2009

#### Assistant Site Manager, Internship

Application supervision at Acıbadem Hospital building of Selenium Twins (BJK Süleyman Seba Complex) construction site.

#### ALPO ENGINEERING, İSTANBUL

Mar 2007 – May 2007

#### 3D Artist

Technical drawings, archviz, urban planning modeling.

#### PROJECTS & RECOGNITION

#### PROGRAMMING PROJECTS

#### 2017 Twiniwt Mobile Game, 6x13 Games

An innovative symmetrical movement puzzle. Globally featured in the AppStore Puzzle and Board categories as well as the AppStore Turkey homepage. It works on all popular mobile and desktop platforms. Uses modified Cocos2d-x game engine, C and C++.

# 2016 **1FPS Retro Game Series, 6x13 Games**4 games that work on all popular mobile and desktop platforms. Uses customized Cocos2d-x and C++.

# 2015 **Fossicker, The Asset Prospector, 6x13 Games**An asset generator that regexp over asset name to create relevant dummies. Powerful plugin system relies on CLOS and Context Oriented Programming.

#### 2014 Riot Game Map Editor, Ekseriya

Map editor, importer/exporter that lets users both define and tile assets on a grid, export & raytrace the scene. Uses Blender Game Engine and Python.

#### 2013 Sprite Automation System, Ekseriya

A system for automated game asset creation work-flow. Uses Python, Blender3D (BPY) and Bash.

# 2013 **Hy Programming Language Blender Integration**Blender Python Module that adds HyLang support and lets users interactively script Blender using Hy.

#### 2012 **CL-IES**

Common Lisp parser/reader and writer for IESNA LM-63 Photometry Standard files.

#### 2011 TwitGraph

CL bubble diagram generator. Searchs & visualizes relationships among a #hashtag and its neighbours.

#### DESIGN PROJECTS

- 2016 **ITU Architecture Program Senior Design Project**Habitation for Syrian refugees, with a focus on integration and employment, in Süleymaniye, İstanbul.
- 2014 **StumpWM Window Manager & HyLang Logos**Winner of StumpWM Official Logo Design Contest.
  Official logo design of Hy Programming Language.
- 2010 Çankaya Ulvi Cemal Erkin Concert Hall & Cultural Center Architectural Design Competition Participation (with Gülsev Özbelen & Gizem Kaya)
- 2010 Nooka International Watch Design Competition Participation with Nooka Ploog-In Design
- 2009 **Akçansa Concrete Ideas Competition**Finalist (with Büşra Atabek)

## COMMUNICATION SKILLS

#### ENGLISH

Listening: C2 (Mastery)\*
 Reading: C2 (Mastery)\*

• Spoken Interaction: C2 (Mastery)\* Spoken Production: C1 (Advanced)\*

• Writing: C2 (Mastery)\*

- Prep Class Nilüfer Milli Piyango Anatolian High School Technical English – ITU Academic Essay Writing – ITU Research Paper Writing – ITU
- Work experience in Baku in a multinational environment for a month. Ensuring communication among Italian, Turkish, Azerbaijani and other parties.

Work experience in Prague for two weeks.

Guidance to several VIP clients including top government officials and corporate executives.

Constant interaction with foreign English speakers via technical/social platforms and mail.

#### **AZERBAIJANI**

- Listening: B2 (Upper intermediate)\* Reading: B1 (Intermediate)\*
- A2 (Elementary)\*
- A1 (Beginner)\*
- Work experience for a month in Baku.
   Several organizations with Azerbaijani clients.

#### TURKISH

- · Native Speaker
- (\*) Common European Framework of Reference for Languages

#### SOFTWARE SKILLS [ © USE | </ > MODIFY | TEACH ]

#### GRAPHICS SOFTWARE

00000	>	Blender 3D
00000		Inkscape
0000		ImageMagick, FFMpeg
00000		GIMP, Photoshop
	>	3D Studio Max, Maya
00000		BI & Cycles Renderers
		Luxrender, Yafaray
00000		AutoCAD, DraftSight
	>	Luminance HDR

#### PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES

	C / C++
>	Common Lisp, Scheme
	Python, Factor
	UNIX / Shell
	Lua, HTML5
	>

#### DEVELOPMENT TOOLS & LIBRARIES

00000		Emacs
		Visual Studio
		GCC, Clang, MSBuild
		GDB, LLDB, Valgrind
		Make, CMake, Gradle
00000		Git Version Control System
00000		Cocos2d-x Game Engine (C++)
	//> //>	Xcode, Android Studio

#### OPERATING SYSTEMS

00000		GNU/Linux (Arch, Debian)
00000		Windows XP/7/8/10
0000		macOS

#### DOCUMENTATION UTILITIES

00000		T <sub>E</sub> X / L <sup>A</sup> T <sub>E</sub> X Systems
00000		Org-Mode, Markdown
00000		Doxygen, Pandoc
0000		MS Office, Libre Office, Scribus

#### ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Hobbies	Walking, Computer Science, Technology Blogging, Literature, Charcoal Drawing
COMMUNITIES	Free / Libre & Open Source Software,

Blender Network, Lisp Game Development, Factor Language Development